as we already said before direct map and
fully associative caches can be
considered to be just special cases or
set associative caches so for example a
direct map cache is actually a one-way
set associative cache and a fully
associative cache is an N wasted
associative cache where n is equal to
the number of lines for all these caches
the address that the processor supplies
is broken into the offset index and tag
components the number of offset bits is
the number of bits that we need to tell
us where in the block size we are so
it's log to a block size the number of
index bits is log 2 of the number of
sets we have in a direct mapped cache
that is the number of blocks we have in
a fully associative cache that's 1 so
log 2 of that is 0 and we have no index
bits and the tag bits are the remaining
bits when you're trying to figure out
which bits are the index bits we
actually need to know which bits are the
offset bits too because knowing that we
have for example 3 index bits doesn't
really tell us whether they're here or
here or here that depends on the offset
bits so make sure that when you are
determining these bits you do it in that
order first figure out how many offset
bits then the next so many bits are the
index bits and then the rest is the tag